Now we're going to decorate our boat.
We're going to be decorating the boat with permanent marker because we don't want any of the colors to run when the boat goes into the water.
The first thing we're going to do is outline different shapes on the boat.
For our design we're going to be making some windows on the top layer.
So, use the black, thin marker.
Permanent marker.
We made our outline and now we're going to fill it in with some colors.
I'm using a blue color now.
We go ahead and do the other side the same with the windows.
It's easier to outline everything first so when you draw, put the actual colors on, they keep their shape and also the border around the different shapes gives a nice, makes it stand out a little more, gives a nice affect to it, has a nice touch.
The next decoration we want to do is we're going to go to the base of the boat and we're going to make kind of a line down which will kind of look like the rim.
I guess like the rubber boarder that goes around the boat so it doesn't bang into anything when it comes close to the dock or when it gets tied up.
So, we'll put a line around the border, around the base of the boat and it won't just be one line we'll actually fill in some other colors to make it stand out a little more.
This is really the key to this one decoration is kind of the key to making it kind of stand out and look like a, somewhat of a real boat.
This is really, even though it may not realize it, this really stands out on boats that you have that thick border going around the base.
So, this will help us make it really look more authentic.
We'll put our first color around, we used a red.
We'll go ahead and take a second color and complete the shape to it.
So we've made two lines and we've made a waved line going down the middle.
Now, the front of our boat needs to have a window so we'll use our thin marker to make our border.
You can experiment with some different markers.
The lines come out not as dark when you're using makers as opposed to if you were going to use some paint.
A type of paint that is good for it is, like we said earlier, the type of paint would be the same paint that's used to decorate cloth like a t-shirt because that's the type of paint that you can throw in the washing machine and it doesn't come off.
Of course when our boat is placed in the water we want the paint to stay on as well.
So, the paint would definitely give it more of a stronger effect but we also wanted to show you that most people have these markers around their house and we wanted to make the project as practical as possible to show you that it can also be done with these markers.
I'll put a little decoration on the flag, we'll just put a star.
You can put your family insignia if you have one.
And here, we see that once the boat is placed into water it actually does float.
So it's a really nice project for kids and they come out with a nice toy that they can play with at bath time.
If you're going to put it into the bath the glue and the color should hold, but I would take out the toothpick, obviously might be a bit of a safety hazard.
But they can have a lot of fun with the boat, soak it up with water, watch it go under, come up again, and it's a lot of fun.